Michael Cooney poster collection, circa 1960s-1982
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Michael Cooney poster collection, circa 1960s-1982 1960-1982
AFC 1982/024
Cooney, Michael B., 1943-
95 items.
6 oversized folders: 1 container (5 folders), 1 oversized folder.
approximately 95 posters: color, black and white; various sizes.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of folk festival posters and concert advertisements featuring Michael Cooney, Joan Baez, Guy Carawan, David Bromberg, Barbara Dane, Jim Garland, John Hammond, Sam Hinton, Bessie Jones, Norman Kennedy, Jim Kweskin, New Lost City Ramblers, Jean Ritchie, Pete Seeger, Peggy Seeger, Frank Stovall, James Taylor, Dave Von Ronk, among others, for various events across the United States, many undated, circa 1960-1982. Some posters are autographed. Includes a few St. Brigid's Day and St. David's Day broadsides.
Provenance
The collection was created by, Michael Cooney; Donation; 1982
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Michael Cooney poster collection, circa 1960s-1982 is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Michael Cooney is a musician, writer, and key contributor to the the American folk revival. He was born in Carmel, California, in 1943, and was raised in Tucson, Arizona. Soon after high school, he traveled the country and his interest in folk and blues music grew. In 1963, he participated in a Young Folksinger's Contest at the Monterey Folk Festival and began performing regularly. By 1964, he began traveling the country and performing in and organizing performances in numerous halls, clubs, coffee shops, and folk festivals throughout U.S., Canada, Mexico, Great Britain, and Europe. He served on several boards including the National Folk Festival and the Newport Folk Festival. As a performer, he participated at most of the major North American folk festivals held in Washington, D.C., Newport, Philadelphia, Mariposa, Winnipeg, Vancouver, Monterey, Berkeley, and San Diego, among many others. He is a longtime contributor and columnist for Sing Out! and has several albums including The Cheese Stands Alone (1968), Singer of Old Songs (1976), Still Cooney After All These Years (1979), Pure Unsweetened (1982), and Together Again (2002).
Scope and Content
The collection includes fliers and posters documenting Cooney’s musical performances and folk festivals he organized between ca. 1960-1982. Posters from performances by several prominent folk music figures, ranging from Pete Seeger to New Lost City Rambers, are included. Information pertaining to the posters are gathered from the items themselves. Most of the fliers and posters are undated but have other pertinent information about who was performing and where the event was taking place.
Arrangement
The Michael Cooney poster collection, circa 1960s-1982 has one series:
Series 1: Posters, ca 1963-1976.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Cooney, Michael B., 1943-
Subjects
Concerts--Posters.; Folk festivals--Posters.; Folk music festivals--Posters.; Folk musicians--United States.
Form/Genre
Broadsides.; Performing arts posters--1960-1980.; Posters.
Container List
- Series 1: Posters, ca. 1963-1976
  - Pete Seeger, June 9, AFC 1982/024:OS01-GR01; color, 11 x 14 1/2 in.
    Pete Seeger sings in concert, Wednesday, June 9 at 8:15 pm, Civic Theatre.
  - Pete Seeger, December 15, AFC 1982/024:OS01-GR02; color, 14 x 11 in.
    Pete Seeger in concert, Friday, December 15th at 8:30pm, presented by the Pittsburgh Folklore Society and Carnegie Ceilidh, Carnegie Music Hall, Oakland.
  - Frank Werner, April 6, AFC 1982/024:OS01-GR03; color, 14 x 11 in.
    Frank Werner an evening of songs and stories, Saturday, April 6th at 8:30pm, presented by the Pittsburgh Folklore Society and Carnegie Ceilidh, Carnegie Lecture Hall, Oakland.
  - Frank George, Aunt Jenny Wilson and Russell Fluharty, October 28, AFC 1982/024:OS01-GR04; color, 14 x 11 in.
    West Virginia traditional instrumental and vocal music, Frank George, Aunt Jenny Wilson, Russell Fluharty, Saturday, October 28th at 8:30pm, presented by the Pittsburgh Folklore Society and Carnegie Ceilidh, Carnegie Lecture Hall, Oakland.
  - Norman Kennedy, Lou Killen, and Maggi Kerr Peirce, November 18, AFC 1982/024:OS01-GR05; color, 14 x 11 in.
    England, Ireland and Scotland Traditional Ballads and Songs, Norman Kennedy, Lou Killen, Maggi Kerr Peirce, Saturday, November 18th at 8:30pm, presented by the Pittsburgh Folklore Society and Carnegie Ceilidh, Carnegie Lecture Hall, Oakland.
  - Gospel Music from the Hill, February 24, AFC 1982/024:OS01-GR06; color, 14 x 11 in.
    Gospel Music from the Hill, Saturday, February 24th at 8:30pm, presented by the Pittsburgh Folklore Society and Carnegie Ceilidh, Carnegie Lecture Hall, Oakland.
  - Pittsburgh Folk Music Concert, March 16, AFC 1982/024:OS01-GR07; color, 14 x 11 in.
    Pittsburgh Folk Music Concert, Saturday, March 16th at 8:30pm, presented by the Pittsburgh Folklore Society and Carnegie Ceilidh, Carnegie Lecture Hall, Oakland.
  - The Masked Marvel, The incredible Bill Hinkley et al., February 12, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR01; black and white, 14 x 8 1/2 in.
    Benefit starring the Masked Marvel, The incredible Bill Hinkley and Judy Larson with Phil Platt, Ceilidh Style, Sunday, February 12, Live at The Extemp.
  - Kingston Ceilidh folk music workshop, September 26, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR02; color, 13 x 7 in.
    Kingston Ceilidh folk music workshop, 8:00pm, Fine Arts Center, URI, September 26th, October 17th, November 14th, and December 12th.
  - Kingston Ceilidh folk music workshop, March 7, AFC 982/024:OS02-GR03; color, 12 x 9 in.
    Kingston Ceilidh folk music workshop, 8:00pm, Recital Hall, Fine Arts Center, URI, March 7th, April 11th, and May 2nd.
  - Kingston Ceilidh folk music workshop, February 21, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR04; color, 14 x 8 1/2 in.
    Kingston Ceilidh folk music workshop, Friday, Friday 21st at 8:00pm, Room C100, Fine Arts Center, URI.
  - The New Lost City Ramblers, February 4, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR05; color, 14 x 11 in.
    The New Lost City Ramblers, presented in concert by the Pittsburgh Folkloric Society and Carnegie Ceilidh in the ballroom of Skibo at the Carnegie Institute of Technology, Saturday, February 4th at 8:30pm.
  - The New Lost City Ramblers, April 29, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR06; black and white, 14 x 11 in.
    The New Lost City Ramblers, Sunday, April 29th at 2:30pm at Hoover High Auditorium.
  - Gospel Blues, March 10, 1967, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR08; black and white, 14 x 11 in.
    The Pittsburgh Folklore Society and the Carnegie Ceilidh present Gospel Blues, Friday, March 10, 1967 at 8:30pm in the Wherrett room of Skibo at the Carnegie Institute of Technology, a concert of traditional music from the hill, The Gospel Lights, The Travelaires, The Golden Rings, et al.
  - British and American folk festival favorites, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR09; color, 11 x 15 in.
    Downtown Sounds/Second Fret Coffeehouse presents a concert series for young and old with British and American folk festival favorites, 7:15 and 9:15 shows.
  - Norman Kennedy, Sara Grey, and Peter R. Hoover, December 9, 1966, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR10; color, 14 x 11 in.
    The Pittsburgh Folklore Society and the Carnegie Ceilidh present a concert of traditional ballads from Scotland and Appalachia with Norman Kennedy, Sara Grey, and Peter R. Hoover, Friday, December 9th 1966 at 8:30pm, Wherrett Rm, Skibo, Carnegie Institute of Technology.
  - The Sixth Annual Berkeley Folk Music Festival Children's Folk Song Concerts, June 28-29, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR11; color, 15 1/2 x 11 in.
    The Associated Students of the University of California present the Sixth Annual Berkeley Folk Music Festival Children's Folk Song Concerts, Pete Seeger and Sam Hinton, Friday and Saturday, June 28 and 29 at 10:30 am, Pauley Ballroom, Bancroft and Telegraph, Berkeley.
  - The Sixth Annual Berkeley Folk Music Festival, June 26-29, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR12; color, 17 x 11 in.
    Workshops, the sixth annual Berkeley Folk Music Festival, presented by the Associated Students of the University of California, June 26-29.
  - Kent State University Folk Festival, January 14-16, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR13; color, 17 x 11 in.
    Kent State University Folk Festival, January 14-16 at 8:00pm.
  - Southern Folk Festival Tour, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR14; color, 15 1/2 x 11 in.
    Southern Folk Festival Tour, Southern Folk Culture Revival Project.
  - Southern Folk Festival Tour, AFC 1982/024:OS02-GR15; color, 15 1/2 x 11 in.
  - Mother Earth concert, March 15, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR01; color, 14 x 8 1/2 in.
    Mother Earth, Sunday, March 15 at 7:30pm at The Electric Factory, produced as benefit for Sing Out Magazine.
  - The Attic, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR02; color, 14 x 8 1/2 in.
    The Attic, 1201 Broadway, Boulder, Colorado, espresso, coffee, entertainment, nightly.
  - Redcar Folk Festival 1968, August 16-18, 1968, August 16, 17, 18, 1968; AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR03; color, 15 x 10 in.
    Redcar Folk Festival 1968, Aug 16th, 17th, 18th, programme and details from the secretary Cutty Wren Folk Club.
  - 2nd Annual Western Regional Folk Festival, October 9-11, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR04; color, 14 x 8 1/2 in.
    2nd Annual Western Regional Folk Festival, October 9, 10, 11, Ft. Barry/Cronkhite in the Golden Gate National Recreation Center area, Co-sponsored by the Nation Folk Festival Association, A National Park Service Bicentennial event.
  - The New England Festival of Folk Music and Craft Fair, August 20-22, 1976, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR05; color, 14 x 8 1/2 in.
    The New England Festival of Folk Music and Craft Fair, New England fiddlers convention and string band reunion, Waterville Valley, NH, August 20-22, 1976.
  - Sign Of The Sun Folk Music, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR06; color, 8 1/2 x 13 in.
    Sign Of The Sun Folk Music, set of four programs begin each evening at 8:30, 4701 College Ave.
  - Barbara Dane, March 15, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR07; color, 11 x 8 1/2 in.
    Barbara Dane, Friday, March 15, 9-1, Bear's Lair Cabaret, sponsored by ASMC Union Program Board.
  - Traditional Kentucky Mountain Folk songs, March 22, 1963, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR08; color, 18 x 12 in.
    13th Ave Gallery presents Traditional Kentucky Mtn, Folk Song sung by Jim Garland, Friday, March 22, 1963, 9pm, 226 S.E. Hawthorne.
  - Micheal Cooney, November 12-17, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR09; color, 8 1/2 x 16 in.
    Micheal Cooney, November 12-17, The Exciting Flamenco Guitar of Carmen Ripepe, Sunday nights.
  - MSU Folk Festival, September 1-October 1, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR10; color, 14 x 8 1/2 in.
    The Ten Pound Fiddle presents The First Occassional MSU Folk Festival, 8pm Friday and Saturday September 1-October 1, MSU Union Building Parlors, presented by the MSU Folksong Society and the ASMSU programing board.
  - Hootenanny, December 6, 7, 13-14, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR11; color, 11 x 17 in.
    Hootenanny -- Sunday 3pm, The First Step 3015 North Campbell, grand opening featuring Michael Cooney and Bob Kimmell appearing Friday and Saturday December 6 and 7 and December 13 and 14.
  - Farewell concert with Michael Cooney March 20, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR12; black and white, 17 x 11 in.
    Michael Cooney, Farewell Concert, War Memorial Hall at 9:00pm, Friday March 20.
  - Woody Gutherie's California to the New York Island with Don Mclean and Michael Cooney, April 20, 1969, AFC 1982/024:OS03-GR13; black and white, 17 x 11 in.
    Pick'n' and Sing'n' Gather'n presents Woody Gutherie's California to the New York Island with Don Mclean and Michael Cooney, Sunday, April 20, 1969, 8pm, Shaker High School Auditorium, Latham, New York, Hudson River Sloop Restoration.
  - One Man Folk Festival with Michael Cooney, April 14, 1972, AFC 1982/024:OS04-GR01; color, 15 1/2 x 5 1/2 in.
    Michael Cooney, One Man Folk Festival, Wright State University Artist and Lecture Series, Friday, April 14, 1972, Oelman Auditorium 8:00pm.
  - Singer of Old Songs, May 1, AFC 1982/024:OS04-GR02; color, 15 1/2 x 5 1/2 in.
    Michael Cooney, Singer of Old Songs, Union Bldg auditorium, Tuesday, May 1.
  - Singer of Old Songs, AFC 1982/024:OS04-GR03; color, 17 x 11 in.
    The Minneapolis Folklore Society Presents: Michael Cooney…singer of old songs, 8:30, February 16 and 17, Walker Church, This concert made possible in part by a grant from the Minnesota State Arts Board.
  - Michael Cooney, September 21, AFC 1982/024:OS04-GR04; color, 11 1/2 x 17 in.
    The Pioneer Valley Folklore Society begins its fall concert series with Michael Cooney, Sunday, September 21, Grace Church Parish Hall, Amherst, 8:00pm, funded in part by the Mass. Council on the Arts and Humanities.
  - Michael Cooney, One-man Folk Festival, Sing Out, The Folksong Magazine, AFC 1982/024:OS04-GR05; color, 17 x 11 in.
    Michael Cooney, One-man Folk Festival, Sing Out, The Folksong Magazine
  - Michael Cooney concert, October 26, AFC 1982/024:OS04-GR06; color, 17 x 11 in.
    Michael Cooney Concert, October 26, 8:00pm, Rutgers Student Center.
  - Li Hibou, September 5-10, AFC 1982/024:OS04-GR07; color, 14 x 10 1/2 in.
    Li Hibou, September 5-10, Guest Artists: Path.
  - One-man Folk Festival, AFC 1982/024:OS04-GR08; color, 17 x 11 in.
    Michael Cooney, One-man Folk Festival.
  - The Bedtime Story and Michael Cooney, September 20, AFC 1982/024:OS04-GR09; color, 17 x 11 in.
    The Bedtime Story and Michael Cooney, Dance and Coffee House, Saturday, September 20th, 8:30pm.
  - One man folk festival with Michael Cooney, September 19, AFC 1982/024:OS04-GR10; color, 17 1/2 x 11 1/2 in.
    U.U.A.B. Coffeehouse presents Michael Cooney "a one-man folk fesitval," Saturday, September 19, 8:30pm, Squire Hall Rathskellar.
  - The Folk Club Magazine, January 1, AFC 1982/024:OS05-GR01; color, 20 x 15 in.
    Buy British Buy Club Folk, The Folk Club Magazine 1/6 on sale here or from Cecil Sharp Hse.
  - The Portable Folk Festival!, AFC 1982/024:OS05-GR02; color, 22 x 17 in.
    The Portable Folk Festival!, [festival poster depicting drawing of bus and concert dates along perimeter].
  - Guy Carawan, April 25, AFC 1982/024:OS05-GR03; black and white, 20 x 14 in.
    The Ballad and Folksong Club presents Guy Carawan, C.S.U. student center theater, 7:30pm, Wednesday, April 25.
  - Peggy Seeger, October 28, AFC 1982/024:OS05-GR04; black and white, 22 x 14 in.
    Peggy Seeger, Concert and Hootenanny, Saturday, October 28, 7:30pm, Temple of Music and Art.
  - Travis Edmonson with Connie Clark and "Those Three Guys," November 5, AFC 1982/024:OS05-GR05; black and white, 22 x 24 in.
    David Graham and Tau Delta Phi presents Travis in concert, Travis Edmonson with Connie Clark and "Those Three Guys," Temple of Music and Art, Sunday, November 5, 8pm.
  - James Taylor, Michael Cooney, David Bromberg, and Electric Cowboy, April 4, AFC 1982/024:OS05-GR06; black and white, 20 x 14 in.
    Benefit concert starring James Taylor and Michael Cooney, David Bromberg, Electric Cowboy, proceeds benefiting Connecticut Citizen's Action Group and Conn - P.I.R.G., Wednesday, April 4th, 7:00p.m., Palace Theater Waterbury.
  - Mike Cooney, January 19, AFC 1982/024:OS05-GR07; black and white, 20 x 14 in.
    Folklore Society, Mike Cooney, Sunday, January 19, 8:00pm, Schwab Auditorium.
  - Michael Cooney, The One-man Folk Festival, April 25, AFC 1982/024:OS05-GR08; color, 19 1/2 x 14 in.
    We all pay for nuclear accidents, Michael Cooney, The One-man Folk Festival in concert for the benefit of the Rochester Safe Energy Alliance, Wednesday, April 25th 8pm at the Unitarian Church.
  - Sing by the Sea, AFC 1982/024:OS05-GR09; color, 22 x 14 in.
    Sing by the Sea, The Philadelphia Music Workshop presents free outdoor musical entertainment at Penn's Landing on the Delaware River, Phila 76 Inc., OPDC Penn's Landing Corp, Phila Maritime Museum, featuring sea chanties, square dancing, gospel, jazz, bluegrass, and folk music from America, the British Isles, and other nations.
  - Michael Cooney, singer of old songs, AFC 1982/024:OS05-GR10; color, 24 x 13 in.
    Michael Cooney, singer of old songs, Front Hall Records [picture of young Michael Cooney sitting with guitar].
  - Michael Cooney, AFC 1982/024:OS05-GR11; color, 18 1/2 x 12 1/2 in.
    Michael Cooney
  - St. Brigid, AFC 1982/024:OS06-GR01; color, 12 x 7 in.
    St. Brigid, Feb. 1, health and prosperity to you in the coming year!, George, Gerry, Becky, and Jenny Armstrong, [Pamphlet depicting drawing of St. Brigid's cross and history].
  - St. David's Day, March 1, AFC 1982/024:OS06-GR02; color, 12 x 7 in.
    St. David's Day, March 1, Why, on St. David's Day, do Welshmen seek To beautify their hat with verdant leek?, Health and prosperity to you in the coming year!, George, Gerry, Becky, Jenny Armstrong.
  - The Pittsburgh Folk Music Society and Carnegie Ceilidh Concert Series, 1967-1968, AFC 1982/024:OS06-GR03; color, 14 x 11 in.
    The Pittsburgh Folk Music Society and Carnegie Ceilidh Concert Series 1967-1968, Carnegie Mellon University.
  - Herb David Guitar Studio, AFC 1982/024:OS06-GR04; color, 15 1/2 x 12 in.
    Herb David Guitar Studio, 209 S. State, 66-58001, [Cover with illustration of a hand and words in Latin].
  - The Folk Shop, AFC 1982/024:OS06-GR05; color, 14 1/2 x 13 in.
    The Folk Shop, Cecil Sharp House, 2 Regents Park Road, London, N.W. 1, [Cover decorated with drawings and words].
  - The Portable Folk Festival, AFC 1982/024:OS06-GR06; color, 17 x 11 in.
    The Portable Folk Festival, [festival poster with announcement in different fonts and autographed signatures]
  - The Portable Folk Festival, AFC 1982/024:OS06-GR07; color, 17 x 11 in.
    The Portable Folk Festival, [festival poster with announcement in different fonts and autographed signatures].
  - The Portable Folk Festival, AFC 1982/024:OS06-GR08; color, 17 x 11 in.
  - The Portable Folk Festival, AFC 1982/024:OS06-GR09; color, 17 x 11 in.
    The Portable Folk Festival, Sponsored by the Newport Folk Foundation, Concerts and workshops in April at Dickenson College in Carlisle, Pennsylvania and Susquehanna University in Selinsgrove, Pennsylvania.
  - The Portable Folk Festival, March 24-25, AFC 1982/024:OS06-GR10; black and white, 17 x 11 in.
    The Portable Folk Festival, Sponsored by the Newport Folk Foundation, Concerts and workshops at Fairfield University March 24-25 [Festival poster with announcement in different fonts].
  - The Portable Folk Festival, March 24-25, AFC 1982/024:OS06-GR11; color, 17 x 11 in.